杰森:我讨厌精神病学大会,麦琪.
Jason: I hate psychiatric conventions, Maggie.
劣质食物,无聊的演讲,简直是三天地狱生活.
Bad food, boring speeches, three days of hell.
跟我来,我们自得其乐多好..
Come with me; we'll have a blast.
麦琪:听起来很轻率,我不会的.
Maggie: As madcap as you make it sound, I can't.
杰森:哦…
Jason: Mmmmm...
麦琪:哦,亲爱的,
Maggie: Oh, honey, you're just upset because the program committee didn't
你不高兴只是因为这个组织委员会今年没让你演讲.
ask you to speak this year.
杰森:不高兴?麦琪,
Jason: Upset?Maggie, please.
得了吧.如果他们想让这个大会被一些新潮医生占领,他们只会写一些无聊,
If they want to load up their convention with trendy doctors who plug
空洞的书,那随他们去好了.
their vacuous books on Donahue, up theirs!
麦琪:这是潮流.
Maggie: That's the spirit.
麦琪:(亲吻)旅途愉快.
Maggie: (kissing) Have a good trip.
杰森:是的,是的.
Jason: Yeah, yeah.
麦琪:再见.
Maggie: Bye.
杰森:再见.
Jason: Bye.
麦琪:早上好!
Maggie: Morning!
埃迪:早上好.
Eddie: Morning.
麦琪:埃迪!
Maggie: Eddie!
埃迪:为什么,西…,我可以说你比前看的可爱多了吗?
Eddie: Why, Mrs.S... may I say you are looking lovelier than ever.
麦琪:埃迪,你在这里干什么?
Maggie: Eddie, what are you doing here?
埃迪:我想闯进迈克的房间,但是他不在家.
Eddie: I tried breaking into Mike's apartment, but he wasn't home.
麦琪:所以你就闯进我们的厨房了?
Maggie: Oh, so you broke into our kitchen instead?
埃迪:自从上次我在来了以后,你把锁换了.
Eddie: Well, you changed the locks since last time I was here.What could I do?
我能做什么呢?迈克到哪里了?
So, where is Mike?
麦琪:哦,他和卢克出去了.
Maggie: Oh, He and Luke are out.
埃迪:哦,迈克还是养了一条狗吗?
Eddie: Oh, Mike finally got himself a dog, huh?
麦琪:不,卢克是我们领养的孩子.
Maggie: No.Luke's a foster child.
埃迪:好多了.他会更有礼貌的.
Eddie: Even better.They come house-broken.
麦琪:他们应该很快就回来.他们去杂货商了.
Maggie: Well, they should be back shortly.They went to the grocery store.
本:好的,灯光,开拍.(尖叫)
Ben: All right, lights, action... (screaming)
埃迪:是的,也很高兴见到你,小傻瓜.拿摄像机干什么?
Eddie: Yeah, it's nice to see you, too, geek breath.What's with the camera?
麦琪:开萝尔在伦敦学习.
Maggie: Carol's studying in London,
我想她要是收到一段录像会很不错的.
and I thought it might be nice if she got a video from us.
埃迪:嘿,我希望把我也拍进去.
Eddie: Hey, I'm willing to send my salivations.
本:要是看到你,她永远都不想回来了…好了,我们开始.
Ben: If she sees you, she'll never want to come back....Okay, we're rolling.
埃迪:嘿,嘿,那是迈克.呃,我要吓他一下.
Eddie: Hey, hey, that's Mike.Uh, I want to surprise him.
迈克和卢克:(尖叫)
Mike and Luke: (screaming)
迈克:嘿!埃迪!你回来了!
Mike: Hey!Eddie!You're back!
埃迪:是的,我会在这里待几天的.
Eddie: Yeah, and I'm gonna be staying here for a few days.
埃迪和迈克:嘿!
Eddie and Mike: Hey!
本:(尖叫)
Ben: (screaming)
埃迪:好了,杰怫逊上来了.他要投三分,他投了,哦,不,球没进.他抢着了蓝板球.他做了个假动作,投篮,进了.
Eddie: All right, Jeff comes dribbling in, goes for three, goes for three, oh no he gets his own rebound, he fakes, he shoots, he scores, woooo!
哇!我们进入加时了!
We're going into overtime!
迈克:哦,不,不,不.埃迪,你赢了.
Mike: Oh, no, no, no.Eddie, you win.
埃迪:哦,来吧,迈克,我手很热,来吧!
Eddie: Well, come on, Mike, I'm hot, man!
迈克:得了吧!我受不了你挂在蓝框上的样子.
Mike: Forget it!I can't stand you hanging on the rim.
埃迪:迈克,你那狂热的生活过的怎么样?
Eddie: Mike, how's that crazy thing I call life?
迈克:哦,我那狂热的生活很好.
Mike: Well, it's that crazy thing I call okay.
埃迪:上次见你时,
Eddie: Last time I saw you,
你在和那个黑不溜湫的冷面公主约会.
you were dating this uptight brunette ice princess.
迈克:我和凯特实际上已经订婚了.
Mike: Kate and I are practically engaged.
埃迪:哦,你没让我说完呢.我希望女人身上的品质是…
Eddie: Well, you didn't let me finish.Qualities I would want in a woman.
迈克:好的,哦,说一说,埃迪,你的工作怎么样?
Mike: Right.Well, uh, tell me Eddie, how's your job?
埃迪:哦,迈克,
Eddie: Oh, Mike, I have just spent the best eight months of my life as
我在一艘海洋游船上当了8个月的服务员.这是我一生中最美好的时光.
a cabin boy for Oceanic Cruises.
迈克:是吗?就像"爱情号".
Mike: Yeah?Like a Love Boat?
埃迪:不,迈克,比那好!
Eddie: No, man, better!Like a Sleaze Boat!
就像童话里一样.船上到处是漂亮,
With a poop deck full of good-looking, mature women.
成熟的女人.迈克,寡妇们都那么的风流.
Mikey, widows are so grateful.
迈克:还是老样子,埃迪.
Mike: Same old Eddie.
埃迪:是的.嘿,
Eddie: Yeah, hey, I got a great idea.
我有个好主意,
What do you say we head down to Miami?
你觉得去逛迈阿密怎么样?游船正在为春季招募小工.
Ships are already hiring towel boys for the spring season.
迈克:噢,埃迪,算了吧,我可不能打个包就走掉.我得负责任.
Mike: Well, Eddie, Come on, I can't just pick up and leave like that.I've got responsibilities.
埃迪:你想谈什么责任?10个光彩照人的姑娘在蒸气浴室,
Eddie: You want to talk responsibilities?
我们提供毛巾.这是多好的差事,兄弟.
Ten glistening babes in a sweat room; no towels.That's a pressure cooker, pal.
迈克:埃迪,我在爸爸工作的社区中心教课呢.
Mike: Eddie, I'm teaching at the community center where my dad works.
埃迪:你?
Eddie: You?
迈克:是的.
Mike: Yeah.
埃迪:你是教师的对头.杜威高中整个数学系的老师因为你都退休了.科尔伯森老师的嗅觉还没有恢复.迈克……
Eddie: You're the anti-teacher!You retired a whole math department at Dewey High.Mr.Colberson still has no sense of smell, Mike.
迈克:真的?
Mike: Really?
埃迪:是的.
Eddie: Yeah.
迈克:哦,这么说,我高中三年还算没白上,对吗?
Mike: Well, my high school years weren't a total waste, right?
卢克:嘿,嘿,伙计们,干什么呢?
Luke: Hey, hey, guys.What's going on?
迈克:哦,我们在回忆一些往事.
Mike: Oh, uh, we're just reliving some old times.
埃迪:哦,卢克小弟,你能和一位大师生活真是幸运.嘿,迈克有没有给你讲过他加入女子游泳队的那件事呀?
Eddie: Oh, Lukie-boy, you are lucky to be living with the master.Hey, did
Mike ever tell you about the time that he actually joined the girl's swim team
卢克:没有.大师先生忘了提了.
Luke: No, his master-ness forgot to mention it.
迈克:我只是一名荣誉队员;我拒绝刮腿毛.
Mike: Well, I was only an honorary member; I refused to shave my thighs.
埃迪:哦,
Eddie: Oh, this guy is too modest.
这家伙还挺谦虚的.
Tell Luke about the time you tied a bunch of weather balloons to Mr.
给卢克讲讲你怎么给德威特先生的大众牌汽车绑上一捆气象气球的?
Dewitt's Volkswagen.
卢克:怎么回事?
Luke: What happened?
埃迪:我们发现德威特先生因此患上了晕机的毛病.
Eddie: Let's just say that's how we found out Mr.Dewitt gets airsick.
卢克:太有意思了!
Luke: That's great!
迈克:是的,那时候,我总是疯疯癫癫的……那都是……错误的,卢克.
Mike: Yeah, it was wacky, it was wild....It was...wrong, Luke.
埃迪:说到疯癫的事儿多着呢.外面才零下几度,把裤子脱了.
Eddie: You know, speaking of wacky, it's 30 degrees outside.Drop your pants.
卢克:啊?
Luke: Huh?
迈克:我和埃迪经常大冬天在外面打篮球.
Mike: Well, Eddie and I used to play basketball outside during the winter.
埃迪:对,穿着短裤打到一个人输得直喊叔叔.
Eddie: Yeah, in just our underwear until one of us cried uncle.
迈克:对,或者哭出来.
Mike: Yeah, or just cried.
卢克:快点,和我多讲点儿这些疯狂的事.
Luke: Come on, tell me more about these wild adventures.
迈克:噢,不,这实在是太无聊了.
Mike: Nah, nah, it's really kind of boring.
埃迪:无聊?操练队伍,
Eddie: Boring?Does the drill team, 50 gallons of peanut butter,
50加仑花生酱和两块软软的蛋糕听起来无聊吗?
and a couple of sponge cakes sound boring?
埃迪:哦,西沃太太,你是用什么密方把这饮料做得这么醇厚,芳香的?
Eddie: Oh, Mrs.S, what is the secret to your hearty, aromatic brew?
麦琪:我把水烧开了.
Maggie: I boil the water.
埃迪:哇呜!为了让我在这里舒服,你实在费尽了心血.
Eddie: Wow!You go through such trouble to make me feel comfortable here.
本:你也别太舒服了;银杯都算上了.
Ben: Don't get too comfortable; the silverware is counted.
埃迪:谢谢你提醒,笨蛋.
Eddie: Thanks for the info, twerp.
本:妖精.
Ben: Leprechaun.
麦琪:好了,本,准备好了吗?
Maggie: Okay, Ben, are you ready?
本:好了,开拍.
Ben: Okay, we're rolling.
麦琪:嗨,开萝尔.本真好,他在拍摄我做家务的镜头.
Maggie: Hi, Carol.Ben was nice enough to tape me doing my daily chores,
所以,宝贝,你就想像着在这儿和我一块洗衣服吧.
so honey you just pretend you're here doing the laundry with me.
本:停!你扮演了一个很不错的妈妈.
Ben: Cut!You're doing a good mom thing here.
我真的很喜欢,不过气氛再活跃点儿会更好.
I'm really buying it, but maybe you could liven it up a little bit.
比如说,你掉了件爸爸的短裤,
You know, let's say you drop a pair of dad's shorts,
然后你去捡的时候踩到了克莉丝的溜冰鞋.
and then as you get up, you slip on Chrissy's skate, and then, um,
然后,我不知道了.
I don't know,
你煮的热咖啡溢出来了.埃迪打我.
you spill boiling hot coffee on, beats me, Eddie.
埃迪:知道吗,西沃医生不在,
Eddie: You know with Dr.
我十分乐意帮你敲打这傻小子.
Seaver away, I'd be more than happy to knock the lad around for you.
麦琪:本,我把这些衣服收拾走以后,我们继续拍.
Maggie: Ben, after I put these clothes away, we're going to do this tape,
要拍就拍的让开萝尔笑起来,要不就不拍.懂了吗?
and it's going to make Carol smile, or we're not going to do it.Understand?
埃迪:听你漂亮妈妈的话,本杰明.
Eddie: You listen to your beautiful mother, Benjamin.
卢克:你说的对,埃迪.溜冰场真是个认识女孩的好地方.
Luke: You were right, Eddie.The skating rink's a great place to meet girls.
埃迪:我怎么说的,小子,学着点吧.
Eddie: What did I tell you, dude, babe-ca-pades.
卢克:我特别喜欢你对付警卫的法子.
Luke: I just loved the way you handled that security guard.
"对不起,长官,我不是故意抓她的.
Sorry, officer, I didn't mean to grab her,
"不过,在我摔倒之前,她是我唯一能抓到的东西."
but she was the only thing between me and an ugly ice-burn."
迈克:埃迪,你不觉得你有点老了,抓不住陌生女人了?
Mike: Eddie, don't you think you're a little old to be groping strange women?
埃迪:哦,伙计,
Eddie: Oh, man, when the day comes I'm too old for that,
当有一天我老的做不了这事了,你就开枪打死我吧.
you can just shoot me.
卢克:别说了,迈克,你感觉没事吧?
Luke: Come on, Mike, you feeling okay?
迈克:是的,我很好.我只是不想溜冰溜进女厕所里.
Mike: Yeah, I'm fine.I just didn't feel like skating into the ladies room.
埃迪:迈克,我这是几个手指头啊?
Eddie: Mike, how many fingers am I holding up here?
本:嘿,各位,
Ben: Hey, guys.I need you to say something nice to Carol.
你们给开萝尔说几句祝福的话.嘿,这是妈妈的主意.
Hey, it was mom's idea.
埃迪:嘿,嘿,你们说咱们刺激刺激她好不好?来吧,这是男人的乐趣.
Eddie: Hey, hey, what do you guys say we moon her?C'mon, guys, it's manly fun.
本:是吗?可是有人太矮了.真的是太"矮"了.
Ben: Yeah? Well, we're one man short. And I do mean "short."
埃迪:他说这话是什么意思?
Eddie: What did he mean by that?
迈克:没什么,埃迪.算了吧,放松点.
Mike: Nothing, Eddie.Come on, relax.
埃迪:好吧,那么今晚谁跟我去食杂店.
Eddie: All right.So, who's up for going to the grocery store tonight?
卢克:我们昨天刚去了.
Luke: We just went yesterday.
埃迪:哦,
Eddie: Yeah, that's cute.
你真伶俐.我说的是城里最热闹的"新舞"俱乐部.
I am talking about the hottest new dance club in town.
游船上的一位女工查丽丝告诉我的.
Charese, one of the ladies from the ship, told me about it.
迈克:食杂店?
Mike: The Grocery Store?
埃迪:哦,是的,迈克.他们有你平衡饮食所需的所有东西.
Eddie: Oh, yeah.Mike, they've got everything you need for a balanced diet.
那里有蛋白质金发女郎,碳水化合物黑肤女郎,
There's blonds for protein, they've got brunettes for carbohydrates,
粗粮红发女郎.
redheads for roughage...
迈克:哦,不,谢谢.不,算了吧,伙计们,我不去.
Mike: Uh, no thanks.Nah, forget it, guys, I'm beat.
埃迪:不,不!
Eddie: No, no!You can't miss this.
你不能不去.迈克,你需要知道口令才能进去.
Mike, you need to know a password to get in.
卢克:嘿,我和你去,埃迪,帮你探探路子.
Luke: Hey, I'll come with you Eddie.Help you squeeze the produce.
埃迪:哦,你好,小兄弟.
Eddie: Well, hello, fellow shopper.
迈克:不,不,不,不,不,埃迪,你忘了,卢克是未成年人.
Mike: No, no, no, no, no.Eddie, you forgot, Luke is underage.
埃迪:我们开始偷偷摸摸地进入这些地方的时候还没他大呢.
Eddie: Well, he's older than we were when we started sneaking into places.
我们只要先从假身份证里找到跟卢克长的像的就行.
We'll just have to dip into the secret stash of fake ID's here.
迈克:埃迪,埃迪!
Mike: Eddie!Eddie!
埃迪:这都是大师的杰作.
Eddie: Behold the work of the master.
卢克:哇!这都是你用的?嘿,约翰尼威尔斯,
Luke: Whoa!You used these?Hey!Johnny Weis, James Marshall, Charlene Woo?
詹姆斯马歇尔,沙林武?看啊,迈克,以前你怎么没让我们看这些东西呢?
C'mon, Mike, how come you never showed me these before?
迈克:哦,因为我不再做这些事了.
Mike: Well, because I don't do that stuff anymore.
卢克:嘿,嘿!
Luke: Hey, hey!This one looks just like me; blond, 5 foot 8.
这个跟我长的很像:金发,5英尺8英寸.今晚我只要长一撮胡子就齐了.
All I have to do is grow a moustache by tonight.
埃迪:哦,迈克,老实告诉你吧,
Eddie: Oh, Mike, I'm telling you man.This Grocery Store is something else.
这个食杂店与众不同.不抓紧时间玩玩,警察说不准就查封了.
We've just gotta get there kinda quick before the vice squad shuts them down.
迈克:埃迪,听我说,算了.
Mike: Eddie, listen to me.Come on.
卢克有家庭作业,今天晚上我哪儿都不想去.
Luke has got homework,
省得被人用催泪瓦斯打倒,
and I don't feel like going to some place tonight where I could get maced
戴上手铐,扔上警车.
and handcuffed to some squad car.
埃迪:好迈克,在今夜的值班员身上试试这个去?
Eddie: Nice Mike, try this on the duty tonight?
迈克:你能不能说点儿别的?我和卢克对这不感兴趣.尤其是卢克.
Mike: Will you just drop this whole thing?Luke and I aren't interested.Especially Luke
埃迪:好吧.
Eddie: All right, we could do something else.
那就干点儿别的.嘿,
Hey, what do you say we go down to the Burger Barn and hassle some high
你们觉得咱们到小卖店去逗逗高中生怎么样?
school kids?
克莉丝:嗨,开萝尔,克里斯蒂娜·林恩·西沃在这里.星期五,放了学,妈妈嗲我去看.
Chrissy: Hi, Carol.Christina Lynn Seaver here.Friday after school, mommy took me to see "Beauty and the Beast."  It stars a beautiful girl named Belle, and a big, hairy beast...
主人公是个漂亮的女孩,名叫贝勒和一只巨大的长毛野兽.
It stars a beautiful girl named Belle, and a big, hairy beast...
本:(扮作野兽)(吼叫)
Ben (dressed as beast): (growling)
本:你这是干什么?
Ben: What did you do that for?
克莉丝:你吓着我了.另外,
Chrissy: You scared me.
该我跟开萝尔讲话,你却把这搞砸了.
Besides, it's my turn to talk to Carol, and you're messing it up.
本:不过,如果这样的话会更有意思.咱们来表演一下野兽怎么抓贝勒.
Ben: But wouldn't it be much more fun if we showed how, you know, the beast grabbed Belle....
克莉丝:妈妈!
Chrissy: Mom!
本:你去哪里?
Ben: Where are you going?
克莉丝:上楼.你有思路了就叫我.
Chrissy: Upstairs.Call me when you get a clue.
迈克:嘿,本,嘿,你看到埃迪了吗?
Mike: Hey, Ben.Hey, have you seen Eddie?
本:没.嘿,也许他到操场去逗女孩了.
Ben: No.Hey, maybe he decided to go down to the playground and hog the swings.
迈克:嘿,妈妈,你看到埃迪了吗?
Mike: Hey, mom.Have you seen Eddie?
麦琪:你刚和他错过.大概15分钟前,他和卢克出去了.
Maggie: You just missed him.He went off with Luke about fifteen minutes ago.
迈克:他们去哪里了?
Mike: Where'd they go?
麦琪:他们说去食杂店买点儿东西.
Maggie: They said they were going to pick something up at the grocery store.
迈克:你竟然让他们去了!
Mike: And you let them go!
本:好吧,妈妈.
Ben: All right, mom.Now you gotta understand.
现在你明白了.这个工作很辛苦,这个工作要连续的干下去.
This is very rough; it's a work in progress.
麦琪:哦,宝贝,
Maggie: Oh, honey, I'm sure it'll be great.
我相信你拍的棒极了.我都等不及了.
I can't wait to see what you've done.
本:(作为播音员)请注意,开萝尔西沃.这是给你的视频邮件.
Ben (as announcer): Attention, Carol Ann Seaver.This is your video letter.
西沃家制作,1992年.下面介绍西沃一家的活动.
Seavermania '92.The Seaver family marches on.
星期六,爸爸又去参加精神病医学会议,
On Saturday, dad was off to yet another psychiatric convention to catch
讨论精神病的最新治疗方法.
up on late-breaking techniques in therapy.
在家里,克莉丝正在学整理床铺.
Back at home, Chrissy's learning to make her bed.
妈妈和爸爸送她一只宠物,
For a reward, mom and dad got her a pet.
克莉丝叫它"小淘气".因为不给它吃东西,
Chrissy named him "Grumpy," 'cause that's how he gets if you don't feed him.
它就胡闹.说到吃的,前几天妈妈做了拿手菜:清蒸金枪鱼.
Speaking of food, the other day, mom made her famous tuna surprise.
你永远的恋人德怀特霍利伯顿经常来我们家.
The love of your life, Dwight Halliburton, drops in all the time.
不止他一个人想你,
Dwight's not the only one who's broken up;
妈妈也想跟你说说心里话.
mom really misses her heart-to-heart talks with you.
这段时间,卢克开始约会了,
Meanwhile, Luke almost had a date, until her mother found out.
结果被女孩的妈妈发现了.迈克自告奋勇地抢占了的你小车,
Mike volunteered to detail your car.
他还用烟熏了你的房间.好了,
He also fumigated your room.
没什么别的要说的了.不过(出现在屏幕上)结束.
Well, there's nothing left to say, but (on-screen) The End.
本:那么,你觉得怎么样,妈妈?很前卫,是不是?
Ben: So.What do you think, mom?Pretty leading-edge, huh?
麦琪:你干得很漂亮,宝贝.
Maggie: Well, it's very clever, honey,
不过你在家里拍的那些画面呢?
but what happened to all that stuff you shot around the house?
本:那些不出彩.
Ben: I'd rather watch kelp.
麦琪:不过,这是家庭的……
Maggie: But it was the family.
本:你是什么看法?
Ben: So what's your point?
麦琪:我觉得你应该加上那些.
Maggie: I think you should put it back in.
本:妈妈,它应该有点风格,这是"本西沃电影制作公司出品".
Ben: Mom, it's gotta have a little style if it's gonna be "une film de Ben Seaver."
麦琪:不,这是"给开萝尔西沃的家信".
Maggie: No, it's "une letter to Carol Seaver."
这是她寄给我们的信.
Here's her last letter that she sent to us.
你看看,然后决定她想看什么.
You read it, and you decide what she wants to see.
大汉: 哇,童子军.没有口令是不准进的.
Bouncer: Whoa, boy scout.You can't come in here without a password.
迈克:哦,没关系.我不想进去;我只是想找个人.
Mike: Oh, that's okay.I'm not trying to get in; I'm just looking for someone.
大汉:是吗,好.我是麦考利·卡尔金,口令!
Bouncer: Yeah, right.And I'm McCauley Caulkin.Password.
迈克:哦,哦,我知道,就在我的嘴边.
Mike: Oh, oh, well I know it.It just slipped my mind.
口令是,呃,香蕉,纸?塑料?
It's, uh, it's uh, bananas.Paper?Plastic?
大汉:错了.笨球儿.
Bouncer: Beat it, slimeball.
迈克:听着,门卫先生,
Mike: Look, uh, Mr.Funt.
这个口令怎么样?警察来巡逻,检查身份证.
How's this for a password; a squadcar full of cops checking ID's?
大汉:这回对了,先生.
Bouncer: Right this way, sir.
迈克:好了,卢克,跟我出去.
Mike: Okay, Luke, you're coming with me.
卢克:你把我与其他人弄混了.我叫加拉尔多.
Luke: You got me mixed up with somebody else.My name's Jeraldo.
梅勒妮:他不是你要找的人.
Melanie: Not the one you think.
埃迪:迈克,这位是查丽丝,这是梅勒妮.她们是寡妇.干嘛不跟我们一起坐会儿.迈克,算了吧,别对女孩子们这么凶嘛.来吧.
Eddie: Mike, this is Charese and Melanie.They're widows.Why don't you take a seat with us, Mike.Come on, don't be rude to the girls.Come on.
卢克:求你了,别让我难堪.
Luke: Please, don't embarrass me.
查丽丝:听着,我有个女朋友和你正好相配.
Charese: You know, I have a friend who is just your type.(laughing) She'll
(笑)她一会儿就跳完了,15分钟以后.
be finished dancing there in fifteen minutes.
迈克:不,谢谢,我在找你.
Mike: No, thanks.I'm seeing someone.
埃迪:嘿,迈克,调调情没事儿,凯特不会知道的.
Eddie: Hey, Mike, it's okay to flirt.Kate's not gonna know.
梅勒妮:谁是凯特?
Melanie: Who's Kate?
埃迪:哦,她是个女看守.
Eddie: Oh, she's the warden.
卢克:她会用鞭子打人,
Luke: The one who cracks the whip.
迈克:对不起,埃迪,我能跟你说一一句话吗?
Mike: Excuse me.Eddie, can I borrow your ear for a second?
埃迪:当然了.
Eddie: Sure.
迈克:我说,你把卢克带到这种地方来,是不是疯了?
Mike: Look, are you crazy for bringing Luke to a place like this?
埃迪:嘿,这是个优雅的地方.你看谁没穿衣服呀?
Eddie: Hey, this is a classy joint.Do you see one spinning tassel?
迈克:埃迪,这跟穿不穿衣服是两码事.
Mike: Eddie, this has nothing to do with spinning tassels.
你不该带一个未成年人到夜总会来.
It has to do with bringing a minor into a nightclub.
埃迪:迈克,你想给我玩保守吗?也许我们可以出去找个地方好好赌一场!
Eddie: Mike, are you turning fogey on me?I mean, maybe we can get out
of here and go find a hot game of bingo
然后明天,我们穿上黑袜子,
And then tomorrow we can put on our dark socks with our plaid shorts,
配上一条花格短裤,
and drive around town at two miles an hour.
以每小时2英里的速度开着车在城里转悠,左眼从头到尾不眨一下.
With our left blinker going the whole time.
迈克:好,你继续笑我吧,
Mike: Fine.Now go ahead and make fun of me, Eddie.
埃迪.
Now you may think that I'm an old fogey,
你可以把我当成老保守,可是我觉得你要把他给带坏了.
but I think you're a bad influence on Luke.
埃迪:嘿,谢谢,伙计.
Eddie: Hey, thanks, man.
迈克:我是开认真的,埃迪.我不想再让你带着他闲逛.
Mike: I'm serious, Eddie.Now I don't want you hanging around with him anymore.
埃迪:为什么?
Eddie: Why?
迈克:因为你下流,你不负责任,
Mike: Because you're sleazy.You're irresponsible, and you're immature.
你不成熟.事实上,我都不知道以前怎么会和你在一起的?
In fact, I don't even know why I hang out with you.
查丽丝:来吧,艾德瓦多,去跳舞.
Charese: Come on, Eduardo, let's dance.
卢克:我在想,该任何表达现在的心情.
Luke: I'm thinking of having my own talk show.
迈克:对不起,加拉尔多,我能跟你说一句话吗?
Mike: Excuse me, Jeraldo.Can I borrow your ear for a second?
麦琪:早上好,亲爱的,吃早餐吗?
Maggie: Morning, sweatheart.Want some breakfast?
迈克:不,谢谢妈妈.我不饿.妈妈,你能回答我一个问题吗?
Mike: No thanks, mom.I'm not hungry.Mom, would you answer me one question?
究竟是什么让你和爸爸着魔而让我和埃迪这个流氓混在一起的?
What on Earth possessed you and dad to ever let me hang out with a jerk
like Eddie?
我是说,我们干尽了坏事,
I mean, we did all kinds of bad stuff.
我们出入夜总会,还偷看X级电影.
We TP'd houses, we snuck into an X-rated movie...
麦琪:怎么个X级?
Maggie: How X?
迈克:我也说不清楚.刚开始看,埃迪就开始喘气.
Mike: Well, I don't know.During the opening credits, Eddie hyperventilated.
麦琪:迈克,我和你爸爸让你和他在一起,是因为你喜欢他.
Maggie: Mike, your dad and I let you hang out with Eddie because you liked him.
迈克:谁会不喜欢呢?
Mike: Well, who wouldn't?I mean, the guy was fun and unpredictable.
那家伙即幽默风趣,又难以预料.
I mean, he was the only guy I knew who could open up a soda bottle
而且我知道只有他能够用拉链打开汽水瓶.
with his zipper.
麦琪:现在什么改变了?
Maggie: So what's changed?
迈克:我!对不起,
Mike: Me!I'm sorry, mom,
妈妈,但到夜总会去,四处乱打招呼早就提不起我的兴趣了.
but calling a restaurant and paging "Seymore Butts" doesn't amuse me anymore.
麦琪:行了,
Maggie: Come on, it's not fair to judge Eddie on pranks he pulled five
根据5年前的印象来判断埃迪是不公平的.
years ago.
迈克:他昨晚还这样.
Mike: He did it last night!
麦琪:那么你认为不和埃迪交朋友,
Maggie: So you think you'd be better off if you and Eddie had never been
你会比现在更出色吗?
friends?
迈克:也许.
Mike: Maybe.
麦琪:迈克,这几年你确实是长大了不少,也许埃迪成长的是有点儿……
Maggie: Mike, you've grown a lot over the past few years.Maybe Eddie's growth is just a little....
迈克:发育迟缓?
Mike: Stunted?
麦琪:得了吧,你们俩从小就是好朋友,
Maggie: Come on, you've been friends since you've been kids.
到现在你们有地方还像.
Eddie's part of who you are today.
迈克:妈妈,我有好几个月没跟谁闹甭了.我只是希望他能够长大.
Mike: Mom, come on, I haven't given someone a wedgie in months.I...I just wish he grow up.
麦琪:什么?和你长的一样?迈克,你想过没有,如果埃迪变了样,他可能就不喜欢你了.
Maggie: What?Be more like you?Mike, did ever puzzle you Eddie stopping.Eddie might not like you?
迈克:你是不管接受或离开他,都不去改变他?
Mike: That's just take him or leave him, just the way he is?
麦琪:对.我敢肯定埃迪的内心也盼望自己快长大……总有一天.
Maggie: Yeah.I'm sure that deep inside Eddie wants to grow up...someday.
迈克:噢,对,
Mike: Oh, right. Here's the man who once told a woman "it's okay,
有个男人对女人说:"这没什么,我没见过乳房,却会设计乳罩".
I'm a blind brassiere designer."
埃迪:我是来拿自己东西的.别担心,
Eddie: Just came to get my stuff.
我很快就下去.
Don't worry, I'll throw myself down the stairs.
迈克:嘿,埃迪,昨晚我说了一大堆蠢话.
Mike: Hey, Eddie, last night I said a lot of stupid things.
埃迪:不,你说的对.
Eddie: Yeah, you got that right.
迈克:而你也做了一大堆的蠢事.
Mike: And then again you did a lot of stupid things.
埃迪:哦,你真会道歉,迈克.此时此刻,真有点"家庭纽带"的味道.
Eddie: Oh, great apology, Mike.This is a real "Family Ties" kind of moment here.
迈克:嘿,行了,埃迪.咱们怎么了?咱们以前多亲密.在说笑话之前,我们先互相攻击和嘲弄一番.
Mike: Hey, come on, Eddie.What happened to us?Huh?We were so tight.I mean, we used to laugh at each other's jokes before we even said 'em.
埃迪:我们的问题是,你现在觉得自己比我好了.
Eddie: What happened was, you started thinking you were better than me.
迈克:不是更好,是不同了.
Mike: Not better; different.
埃迪:是更好.
Eddie: Better.
迈克:是不同.我是说我有了稳定的恋人.
Mike: Different.I mean, I am in a steady loving relationship,
而你在追求无知的寡妇.
and you prey on innocent widows.
我有了一份可靠的工作,
I mean, and I have a responsible job,
而你却在船上的澡堂里给人递毛巾.
and you hock towels at a floating bathhouse.
我在努力帮着抚养一个16岁的孩子,
And I'm trying to help raise a 16-year-old boy,
免得他以后会变得像…..
so he doesn't turn out to be someone....
埃迪:像我?
Eddie: Like me?
迈克:(叹气)我的做派好像我比你出色.
Mike: (sighing) I have been acting like I'm better than you.
埃迪:这就是你的结论.
Eddie: The prosecution rests.
迈克:埃迪,也许我现在真的像老保守了.
Mike: Eddie, maybe I have been acting like an old fogey.
但是听我说,我也不知该怎么做.
But listen, I don't have all the answers.
见鬼,
I mean, heck, sometimes I'm standing in front of my class,
有时候我站在教室的前面,就特别想教他们吐唾沫球,
and all I wanna do is help 'em make spitballs,
因为我和你比他们谁都吐的好.
because you and I made 'em better than they ever could.
埃迪:现在的孩子们,太没追求了.
Eddie: Kids today; no attention to quality.
迈克,你以为我愿意一辈子做澡堂服务员?
Mike, do you think I want to be a towel boy forever?
我看看你,再对比一下我自己,
I look at you, and I think, compared to me, you really got it together.
你的才叫生活.如果我这辈子做不出什么事来怎么办?
What if I never make anything of my life, huh?
迈克:噢,别这样,埃迪.嘿,
Mike: Aw, come on Eddie.Hey, you got loads of time.
时间还长着呢,你既聪明又讨人喜欢,你会有所成就的.
You're smart, and you're likeable.I mean, it'll happen for you.
埃迪:这是我的想像,还是我们俩就是分不开?
Eddie: Am I imagining, or we got a bonding thing going here?
迈克:嘿,我从没看你这么有,怎么说?人情味.我喜欢你这样.
Mike: Hey, I've never seen you this, I don't know, human.I like it.
埃迪:是啊,真是太棒了,是吗?
Eddie: Yeah.This is great, huh?
迈克:是的,不是吗?
Mike: Yeah, isn't it?
埃迪:是的.如果你也这样,寡妇们会吃掉你的.
Eddie: Yeah.If you buy this, the widows are gonna eat it up.
麦琪:杰森,真高兴你回来的正巧,
Maggie: Jason, I'm so glad you got back in time to see the video Ben made
看看本给开萝尔拍的录像.
for Carol.
克莉丝:我坐在爸爸身边.
Chrissy: I'm sitting next to daddy.
本:好的.
Ben: All right.Now don't expect too much;
现在不要期待太多;我还要剪掉3个小时的内容呢.
I still have to cut three hours out of this.
杰森:哇!
Jason: Whoa!
麦琪:不,只是开玩笑.他逗我们呢.开始吧,亲爱的,放吧.
Maggie: No, just kidding.He's kidding.Go ahead, honey.Roll it.
本:亲爱的开萝尔,我听说你有些想家.
Ben: Dear Carol, I heard you were feeling a little homesick.Well cheer up.
振作点,只有最优秀的人离开自己深爱的人的时候,才会这样的.
It happens to the best of us when we're away from the people we care about.
我们希望这盘录像能够给你带去微笑,并你带回到家里.
We hope this video will bring you a smile, and remind you of home.
麦琪:嘿,开萝尔.本真好,他在拍摄我做家务的镜头.
Maggie: Hi, Carol.Ben was nice enough to tape me doing my daily chores,
所以,宝贝,你就想像着在这儿和我一块洗衣服吧.
so honey you just pretend you're here doing the laundry with me.
克莉丝:今天是我的生日,是真的.我该点几根蜡烛?1,
Chrissy: It's my birthday, yes indeed.How any candles do I need?
2,3岁了,4,5,6岁了,
One, two, three years old.Four, five, six years old.
就这些.你还想让我做什么?
That's it, what else do you want me to do?
本:说再见.
Ben: Say goodbye.
克莉丝:再见,开萝尔.哦,还有,快点回家.本把我逼疯了.
Chrissy: Goodbye, Carol.Oh, P.S., come home quick.Ben's driving me crazy.
本:现在,嗯,
Ben: Now, uh, Carol, uh, in answer to your letter; I miss you, too.
开萝尔,回复你的来信:我也想你.我知道我们不太一样,
I know we've had our differences, but I care about you,
但我在意你,希望你快点回来.
and I want you to come home soon.
麦琪:太棒了,亲爱的.
Maggie: That was terrific, honey.
杰森:我们为你骄傲,本.
Jason: We're proud of you, Ben.
本:哦,还没结束呢.
Ben: Well, it's not finished yet.
我还要拍全家人向开萝尔挥手的镜头.
I want to get one more shot of the whole family waving to Carol.
麦琪:哦,太好了.迈克去哪了?
Maggie: Well, that's great.Where's Mike?
迈克:(外边)加油,加油啊!
Mike (outside): Come on, come on!
克莉丝:怎么回事啊?
Chrissy: What's that?
迈克:快点,冲啊,冲啊.
Mike: Come on, let's go, let's go!
埃迪:投篮,快点,小鸡,你不用这样!
Eddie: Shoot it, come on, chicken, you don't want that!
杰森:孩子们,外边零下好几度呢,你们干什么呢?
Jason: Guys, it's 40 degrees out here.What are you doing?
迈克:把这条小黄鼠狼的尾巴冻掉!
Mike: Freezing this little weasel's tail off!
埃迪:哦,是吗?好吧,看看谁是黄鼠狼.
Eddie: Oh, yeah?Well, we'll see who the weasel is!
迈克:没中!
Mike: Missed!
杰森:麦琪,他们穿着短裤打球呢.
Jason: Maggie, they're playing in their underwear.
麦琪:我知道,不是很好吗?
Maggie: I know; isn't it wonderful?
本:各位,快点,向开萝尔挥手.
全家:再见,开萝尔.快点回来.我们想你.
00:22:05,800
Ben: Everybody, come on, wave to Carol. Entire family: Bye, Carol.Come back soon.We miss you.